[
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Deputy Secretary in the Department of Expenditure under the Central Staffing Scheme?",
        "options": [
            "Sanjay Malhotra",
            "T.V. Somanathan",
            "Girish Chandra Murmu",
            "Mrithinjai Srikanthan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Mrithinjai Srikanthan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was elected as the new Prime Minister of Vanuatu in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Stephen Felix",
            "Charlot Salwai",
            "Jotham Napat",
            "Ishmael Kalsakau",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Executive Officer of Standard Chartered India, effective April 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Zarin Daruwala",
            "Deepak Parekh",
            "P D Singh",
            "Aditya Puri",
            "Mohak Singh"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the captain of Royal Challengers Bengaluru (RCB) for IPL 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Virat Kohli",
            "Faf du Plessis",
            "Rajat Patidar",
            "Glenn Maxwell",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been nominated as the U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for South Asian Affairs, replacing Donald Lu?",
        "options": [
            "Richard Verma",
            "Paul Kapur",
            "Nisha Biswal",
            "Vivek Murthy",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was confirmed as the U.S. intelligence chief in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Daniel Coats",
            "Robert Brook",
            "Tulsi Gabbard",
            "Avril Haines",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been given the additional charge as Secretary of the Ministry of New and Renewable Energy (MNRE)? (Jan 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Alok Ranjan",
            "Nidhi Khare",
            "Rajiv Singh",
            "Preeti Sharma",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed Director of the Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "S. Somanath",
            "R. Umamaheswaran",
            "P. Kunhikrishnan",
            "M. Mohan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Director General (DG) of the Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) as of January 3, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Vikram Dev Dutt",
            "Dinesh Chand Sharma",
            "Faiz Ahmed Kidwai",
            "Rajiv Bansal",
            "Arun Kumar"
        ],
        "answer": "Faiz Ahmed Kidwai"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been reappointed as Ireland's Prime Minister (Taoiseach) for the second time in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Micheál Martin",
            "Enda Kenny",
            "Leo Varadkar",
            "Mary Lou McDonald",
            "Laurie Brentford"
        ],
        "answer": "Micheál Martin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been sworn in as the 25th Governor of Mizoram? (Jan 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Anil Chauhan",
            "V K Singh",
            "Arvind Kumar",
            "Manoj Sinha",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as an independent observer for Chandigarh's mayoral election on January 30?",
        "options": [
            "Justice (retd) Jaishree Thakur",
            "Justice (retd) Kurian Joseph",
            "Justice (retd) Deepak Gupta",
            "Justice (retd) Madan Lokur",
            "None of the abocve"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice (retd) Jaishree Thakur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Ombudsman and Ethics Officer of the Board of Control for Cricket in India? (January 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Sourav Ganguly",
            "Justice Arun Mishra",
            "Prabhtej Singh Bhatia",
            "Devajit Saikia",
            "Jay Shah"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice Arun Mishra"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Director General of the Bureau of Police Research and Development (BPR&D) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Barinder Jeet Singh",
            "Neeru Garg",
            "P Renuka Devi",
            "Senthil Avudai Krishna Raj S",
            "Brajesh Punia"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Secretary of the Department of Higher Education, Ministry of Education?",
        "options": [
            "Rajesh Kumar Sinha",
            "Vineet Joshi",
            "Alok Kumar Gupta",
            "Pankaj Choudhary",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been selected for the Ayyan Thiruvalluvar Award for 2025, announced by the Tamil Nadu government?",
        "options": [
            "M. Padikkaramu",
            "Viduthalai Rajendran",
            "L. Ganesan",
            "Kabilan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was elected as the President of Lebanon in January 2025, ending a two-year power vacuum?",
        "options": [
            "Michel Aoun",
            "Hassan Diab",
            "Joseph Aoun",
            "Najib Mikati",
            "Benjamin Frank"
        ],
        "answer": "Joseph Aoun"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been reappointed as the MD & CEO of IDBI Bank for another three-year term starting March 19, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Amitabh Chaudhry",
            "Sandeep Bakshi",
            "Sumant Kathpalia",
            "Rakesh Sharma",
            "Byomkesh Shastri"
        ],
        "answer": "Rakesh Sharma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the chairperson of the Athletics Federation of India's (AFI) Athletes Commission?",
        "options": [
            "P. T. Usha",
            "Anju Bobby George",
            "Mary Kom",
            "Hima Das",
            "Deepa Karmakar"
        ],
        "answer": "Anju Bobby George"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the officiating Director General of the CRPF following the retirement of Anish Dayal Singh?",
        "options": [
            "Vitul Kumar",
            "R.K. Vishwakarma",
            "Alok Kumar",
            "Sunil Raj Awasthee",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was sworn in as a Supreme Court judge on January 16, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Justice R. Banumathi",
            "Justice S. Ravindra Bhat",
            "Justice K Vinod Chandran",
            "Justice Siddappa Sunil Dutt Yadav",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice K Vinod Chandran"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who among the following has been elected as a board member of the Marylebone Cricket Club (MCC) Advisory Board in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Kumar Sangakkara",
            "Jay Shah",
            "Sourav Ganguly",
            "Rahul Dravid",
            "Sanjay Bangar"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chairman and Managing Director (CMD) of the Food Corporation of India (FCI)? (January 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Rajiv Bansal",
            "Anil Kumar Jain",
            "Ashutosh Agnihotri",
            "Ajay Bhushan Pandey",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Ashutosh Agnihotri"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of NASSCOM Foundation with immediate effect from January 2, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Nidhi Bhasin",
            "Jyoti Sharma",
            "Debjani Ghosh",
            "Aruna Sundararajan",
            "Ritu Anand"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor has been appointed as the first Brand Ambassador for FICCI Frames?",
        "options": [
            "Kartik Aaryan",
            "Ayushman Khurana",
            "Vicky Kaushal",
            "Ranveer Singh",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Ayushman Khurana"
    }
]